<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>machine-learning on Richard's Blog</title><link>https://richardcsuwandi.github.io/blog/tags/machine-learning/</link><description>Recent content in machine-learning on Richard's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://richardcsuwandi.github.io/blog/tags/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Gaussian Process Regression using GPyTorch</title><link>https://richardcsuwandi.github.io/blog/posts/gp-regression/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://richardcsuwandi.github.io/blog/posts/gp-regression/</guid><description>Gaussian Process, or GP for short, is an underappreciated yet powerful algorithm for machine learning tasks. It is a non-parametric, Bayesian approach to machine learning that can be applied to supervised learning problems like regression and classification. Compared to other supervised learning algorithms, GP has several practical advantages: it can work well on small datasets and has the ability to provide uncertainty measurements on the predictions.
In this tutorial, I am going to demonstrate how to perform GP regression using GPyTorch.</description></item><item><title>Why the Future of AI is Federated</title><link>https://richardcsuwandi.github.io/blog/posts/federated-learning/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://richardcsuwandi.github.io/blog/posts/federated-learning/</guid><description>As technology advances, AI is becoming more and more integrated into our lives. Numerous industries and companies are using AI to improve their products and services. For instance, Google uses machine learning to build personalized services and maximize user experiences. Unfortunately, it also comes with a challenge as such models need to be trained on tons of personal data in order to perform well. This certainly becomes an issue as we are increasingly concerned about privacy.</description></item><item><title>Why Is AI So Smart and Yet So Dumb?</title><link>https://richardcsuwandi.github.io/blog/posts/moravec/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://richardcsuwandi.github.io/blog/posts/moravec/</guid><description>Have you ever wondered why AI has such an easy time doing stuff that we find very hard? But having a hard time doing stuff that we find very easy?
Moravec&amp;#39;s Paradox
In the 1980s, an AI researcher named Hans Moravec wondered the exact same thing. As Moravec put it:
&amp;ldquo;It is comparatively easy to make computers exhibit adult level performance on intelligence tests or playing checkers, and difficult or impossible to give them the skills of a one-year-old when it comes to perception and mobility.</description></item><item><title>Data is the New Lego</title><link>https://richardcsuwandi.github.io/blog/posts/lego/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://richardcsuwandi.github.io/blog/posts/lego/</guid><description>When I was a kid, I used to love playing with Lego. My brother and I built almost all kinds of stuff with Lego — animals, cars, houses, and even spaceships. As time went on, our creations became more ambitious and realistic. There were also times when we could each have insisted that our Lego was our own, till we realized that pooling resources would eventually help us went further. We were growing up too, and as our playing became more sophisticated, we learned how to make better models.</description></item><item><title>I Taught My Computer to Classify Chinese Calligraphy Styles</title><link>https://richardcsuwandi.github.io/blog/posts/chinese-calligraphy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://richardcsuwandi.github.io/blog/posts/chinese-calligraphy/</guid><description>Motivation
As an international student studying in China, I’ve always been fascinated by the diversity of Chinese culture and history. This motivated me to build a Chinese calligraphy classifier.
There are multiple styles of calligraphy, which mainly belong to different dynasties. Each of them has its way of shaping and arranging the character. For this project, I picked four styles:
Seal Script (篆書 zhuanshu) Cursive Script (草書 caoshu) Clerical Script (隸書 lishu) Standard Script (楷書 kaishu) If you&amp;rsquo;re interested, you can read more about these different styles here.</description></item><item><title>5 Reasons Why Data Science Is Like Cooking</title><link>https://richardcsuwandi.github.io/blog/posts/5-reasons/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://richardcsuwandi.github.io/blog/posts/5-reasons/</guid><description>Data science is a lot like cooking. Although raw ingredients may be fascinating at first, the fun doesn't start until you're actually able to start slicing, dicing, and eventually serving up something delicious to devour. Most of the time, you'll end up with a dish, but in the data science world, we call it data insights. In this blog post, I want to share 5 analogies of data science to cooking which helped me understand the field better.</description></item></channel></rss>